🛘 (+91) 97855-29088 | 🗷 jitesh_j@cs.iitr.ac.in | 🏕 praeclarumjj3.github.io | 🖸 praeclarumjj3 | 🗖 jitesh-jain-1451b9192/

"All progress takes place outside the comfort zone."

Summary_

An undergrad researcher, diving deep into the world of Artificial Intelligence, trying to find solutions to the unanswered problems in the field of Al to help humanity. Familiar with concepts in deep learning, linear algebra, probability and statistics, and computer science fundamentals.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Roorkee, India

B.TECH. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2019 - Exp. 2023

· CGPA: 9.286/10

Central Academy, Kota

Kota, India

GRADE 12 (SENIOR SECONDARY LEVEL)

2019

• Percentage: 96.60%

Modern Senior Secondary School, Kota

Kota, India

GRADE 10 (SECONDARY LEVEL)

2017

• CGPA: 10/10

Experience _____

Picsart Remote

RESEARCH INTERN June, 2021 - Present

- Working with the **Picsart AI Research** team at *Picsart*.
- Working on developing an efficient Real-Time Semantic Segmentation Framework.

SHI Lab, University of Oregon

Remote

Remote)

November, 2020 - Present

VISITING STUDENT RESEARCHER

· Working with Prof. Humphrey Shi. • Working on developing a Unified Object Level Image Editing/Completion Framework.

FilterPixel

ML ENGINEER INTERN July, 2020 - September, 2020

- Worked on developing ML models for automating the process of Photo Culling. [Link]
- Developed ML models for classifying images based on their exposure, blurriness, etc.
- [Letter of Recommendation]

Publications_

DEAP Cache: Deep Eviction Admission and Prefetching for Cache

September, 2020

AYUSH MANGAL* | JITESH JAIN* | KEERAT KAUR GULIANI* | OMKAR BHALERAO*

Vision and Language Group, IIT Roorkee

- This is the **first** time an approach has tried learning all the three policies: Admission, Prefetching and Eviction.
- Unlike, previous methods which relied on past statistics for carrying out cache replacement, we predict future statistics (frequency and recency) and then use an online RL-algorithm for eviction.
- [PrePrint] [GitHub]

SHI LAB, UNIVERSITY OF OREGON

Projects.

AOT-GAN-Experiments Remote

May 2021

- AOT-GAN was proposed in the paper: Aggregated Contextual Transformations for High-Resolution Image Inpainting.
- Conducted various experiments to evaluate GAN Loss' efficiency during AOT-GAN's training on the Places2 Dataset for Image Inpainting using the Pytorch Framework. [GitHub]

JITESH JAIN · CV

BackBone Profile Remote

SHI Lab, University of Oregon

December 2020

- Most of the Segmentation works use networks pretrained on Imagenet as bacbones for feature extraction.
- Conducted Experiments on various networks like ResNet 18/34/50/101, MobileNetv2, Xception Net used in Segmentation works as backbones
 to evaluate their inference time performance metrics.. [GitHub]

ChatBot with Pytorch IIT Roorkee

SELF-LEARNING PROJECT | VISION AND LANGUAGE GROUP

June 2020

- Chatbots are based on the sequence-to-sequence modeling task.
- Implemented a chatbot using pytorch on the Cornell Movie-Dialogs Corpus dataset using GRUs with an Attention mechanism. [GitHub]

VQ-VAE Implementation in Pytorch

IIT Roorkee

SELF-LEARNING PROJECT | VISION AND LANGUAGE GROUP

May 2020

- Implemented VQ-VAE from scratch in Pytorch on the MNIST dataset as a self-learning project. [GitHub]
- Derived conclusions based on the training and testing results regarding the encoding of images into a latent space, adding Vector-Quantization
 to encodings and generating images.

Honours & Achievements

2019 All India Rank - 252, Joint Entrance Exam (JEE) Advanced is attempted by more than 230,000 students [Link]

2019 **All India Rank - 454**, Joint Entrance Exam (JEE) Main is attempted by more than 1,000,000 students.

KVPY Fellowship Holder, KVPY is a highly prestigious National Fellowship awarded by Indian Institute of

Science and Government of INDIA to students who show high aptitude in research. [Link]

NTSE Scholarship Awardee, NTSE is a national level examination for secondary school level to identify and recognize students with high intellect and skills. [Link]

Skills.

Programming Languages Python, Java, Dart, Swift, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Packages and Environments Pytorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Android Studio, Flutter, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Lucent, Sckit-learn, Opencv, Django

Utilities Git, Linux Shell, Vim

Relevant Courses (online) Deep Learning Specialization (Coursera), GAN Specialization (Coursera) by DeepLearning.ai

CS231n (Computer Vision Course) by Stanford University, CS229 (Machine Learning Course) by Stanford University

Stat 110 (Probability and Statistics) by Harvard University,

Relevant Courses (offline) Mathematics-I (Linear Algebra and Calculus), Optimisation Techniques

Discrete Structures, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems

Extracurricular Activity

Vision and Language Group, IIT Roorkee

Roorkee, India

CORE MEMBER

January, 2020 - Present

- Core member of VLG IITR, a student group that promotes **Deep Learning research culture** at IITR by discussing relevant research papers, organizing workshops and working on related projects. **[Link]**
- Conducted a workshop on Generative Modelling using GANs in March 2021. [Colab Notebook]

Mobile and Development Group

Roorkee, India

ANDROID APP DEVELOPER

January, 2020 - Present

- Developer at the Mobile Development group based in IIT Roorkee. [Link]
- · Involved in contributing to open-source projects, developing android applications in Flutter, etc.

Geek Gazette, IIT Roorkee Roorkee, India

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

August, 2019 - Present

• Official Tech Magazine based in IIT Roorkee.[Link]

Involved in designing graphics for articles and other design related decisions.

JITESH JAIN · CV